# Stephan Osterburg

San Francisco Bay Area, CA, USA M +1 (415) 630-0194

Email: stephan.osterburg@icloud.com

Skype: <u>stephanosterburg</u>
Blog: <u>stephanosterburg.com</u>
GitHub: <u>stephanosterburg</u>

# **Profile**

Computer graphics expert with comprehensive experience in post-production, animation, software engineering and visual effects, and a background in architecture. Project planning and management. Actual proficiency in teamwork and team building, fostering an open team collaboration environment. Mentoring, teaching, and coaching; defining clear direction, expectations, and standards. A keen eye for details. – A lifelong thirst for discovering and learning new skills.

# **Experience**

#### SENIOR TECHNICAL ARTIST

**IMVU** 

Feb 2020 - present

- Created character body and face rigs for game engine (Godot)
- Develop workflow and other tools for Maya (Python/Python API)
- Develop Machine Learning models and workflows for character deformations

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER (Contractor)**

Pixelgun Studio

Nov 2019 - Jan 2020

- Developed and implemented pipeline tools (Python)

#### **TECHNICAL LEAD (Creature FX)**

Framestore

May 2017 - Jun 2018

- Developed and implemented character pipeline for the movie "Christopher Robin" (2018)
- Created UI in Maya (Python/PySide) utilizing Shotgun to load character(s) and their asset(s) in the shot
- Wrote an auto-rig tool in Python utilizing Maya and Qualoth to set up a character and apply the animation in the shot, saving in average three plus hours of setup time per character/shot

#### **TECHNICAL LEAD (Rigging)**

#### PDI/DreamWorks Animation

Sep 2002 - Feb 2017

- Set creative and technical direction in collaboration with the CTD Department Head
- Performed weekly rounds with artists and evaluated artist work
- Supervised the Character TD's on creative, technical and time management issues
- Oversaw technical development and optimization efforts and coordinated effort with other shows
- Oversaw motion system, and body deformations work for the film to satisfy creative and technical requirements while meeting the production schedule
- Mentored and directed the work of the CTDs working on tasks under my domain
- Setup character templates and recommend alternate approaches or simplifications to keep the CTD work under budget
- Identified and prioritized R&D software bug fixes & feature requests
- Wrote Python helper scripts to optimize character setup workflow
- Converted deformation operators from PDI script into C++ as well as developed new once
- Converted the node based motion system into a Python library, i.e. arm, digit (finger), shoulder motion system to be integrated into the new rigging software including a UI (PySide) to build a characters motion system

<u>Projects:</u> Shrek, Madagascar, Megamind, Mr. Peabody and Sherman, Kung Fu Panda, Trolls, Larrikins etc.

#### **CG SUPERVISOR/ANIMATOR**

#### **Pacific Data Images**

Sep 1998 - Sep 2002

- Integrated industry tools, such as MAYA, into the company's animation pipeline
- Wrote Python pipeline tools to help the interaction between third party software and PDI's
- Worked with R&D to transfer part of the PDI's proprietary software over to MAYA

#### Projects:

- Served as a VFX and CG Supervisor for national commercials working with high-profile clients such as Saturn,
   Coca- Cola, Kool-Aid, Sega, and Monster.com
- Supernova, Mission: Impossible II, A.I. Artificial Intelligence, Forces of Nature, Minority Report

#### **HEAD OF CG DEPARTMENT**

#### Das Werk

Mar 1996 - Jul 1998

- Established a CG department to expand the visual effects segment of the business
- Secured high-profile clients with responsibility for bidding, negotiation, and project management
- On-set VFX Supervisor and CG Supervisor managing film breakdowns and motion captures, etc.
- Assured each project complied with time and budget requirements
- Managed multiple teams

Projects: Run Lola Run, Winterschläfer, Siemens - Fantasy for an Age, BMW - VIV / Pave Purple

# **Additional Experience**

- <sup>-</sup> CG Supervisor / Technical Director, FREELANCE, Munich, Germany
- Senior Animator, BIBO TV, Frankfurt am Main, Germany
- Application Consultant, ALIAS, Munich, Germany
- Software Engineer, VIERTE ART, Munich, Germany
- Graphics Operator, A.V. HARTWIG/MULTIVIDEO, Munich, Germany
- Modeling Artist, STEINER FILM, Munich, Germany

## Skills

- Languages: German (native), English (fluent)
- Strong mentorship, teamwork, managerial and leadership experience
- Excellent communication, analytical, and organization skills
- Proven ability to interact with all levels of the organization, including senior leadership and executives
- Extensive professional experience with a broad technical skillset:
  - Software Development
    - proficient: Python, Keras/TensorFlow, Dask, Pandas, Numpy, scikit-learn, SQL, spaCy, GitHub, Jira
    - moderately proficient: Docker, PySpark, DevOps (AWS, Paperspace, DigitalOcean), Javascript, Tableau
    - <sup>-</sup> prior experience: PDI Script (proprietary), C, C++, C#, Perl, Ruby, Java, Fortran, Assembly, Basic
  - Software: PDI (proprietary), Maya, Houdini, Unreal, Unity, Nuke, Alias, Wavefront, 3DEqualizer

#### **Education**

- Data Scientist/Machine Learning Engineer Diploma, FLATIRON SCHOOL April 2019
- Software Engineering Diploma, CONTROL DATA INSTITUTE December 1989
- Architectural CAD/CADD Diploma, IVM TECHNICAL CONSULTANT March 1989
- Architectural Draughtsman, ARCHITECT OFFICE BIENERT March 1984

### **Achievements**

- Co-Authored MEL Scripting for Maya Animators (First Edition) by Mark Wilkins & Chris Kazmier
- Siggraph 2008 presentation: Art-Directable Dynamic-Hair Shells in Madagascar: Escape 2 Africa